A Guide to the Directors' Correspondence of the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1933-1977 (bulk 1934-1976)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
A Guide to the Directors' Correspondence of the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts 1933-1977 (bulk 1934-1976)
The Library of Virginia
33863, 44067
81.85 cu. ft., 91 boxes
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Biographical Information
The Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, the nation's first state-supported art museum, opened to the public on 16 January 1936, "to promote education in the realm of art throughout the commonwealth," (Section 9-78, Code of Virginia). A partnership between private donors and state legislators, the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts was established following the 1919 donation from John Barton Payne, jurist, and discriminating art collector, gave a collection of paintings to the Commonwealth. The Payne donation and other works of art needed a permanent home that could provide exhibit and storage space - something the Commonwealth did not have at that time. In response to this need for a permanent home for state-owned art collections, Payne donated $100,000 to be used for the construction of a state museum. On 27 February 1932, the donation was conditionally accepted (Acts of Assembly 1932, Chapter 70). Governor John Garland Pollard led a campaign to raise additional private funds, and promoted the use of state revenue for operating expenses. Additional monies from the Federal Works Project Administration completed the funding, and in 1934 the General Assembly designated the site for the building on the grounds of the Robert E. Lee Camp Soldiers' Home at Boulevard and Grove avenues, named it the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, and vested control and management in a Board of Trustees.
From the establishment of the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, the Board of Trustees was given full power and authority to manage, control, maintain, and operate the Museum. The Board numbers from 25 to 35 members appointed by the Governor. Ex-officio members are the Governor, Lieutenant-Governor, speaker of the House of Delegates, and the Mayor of Richmond. Terms of office are limited to five years, with no person eligible to serve consecutively more than two terms. The Board determines policy, and selects a Director to carry out Museum operations. Directors and their dates of service: Thomas C. Colt, Jr., 1935-1948; Leslie Cheek, Jr., 1948-1968; James M. Brown, 1969-1976; R. Peter Mooz, 1976-1981; Paul N. Perrot, 1984-1991; Katharine C. Lee, 1991-2000; Michael Brand, 2000-2005; and Alexander L. Nyerges, 2006 -. During World War II, Thomas C. Colt, Jr. took a leave of absence from the Museum to reenlist in the military. In his place, Beatrice von Keller and Violet MacDougall Pollard became Associate Directors of the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, overseeing Museum operations during Mr. Colt's absence.
Over the history of Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, the physical building has undergone many additions and renovations. In 1954, using state appropriations and private philanthropy, a north wing was added to increase gallery space and house a 530-seat theatre with a professionally equipped stage. The 1970 south wing, financed solely by the state, restored the originally-conceived Georgian style rectangle. This wing increased gallery space and expanded operational facilities. The later north wing, also funded by the state, opened in 1976, adding three more galleries, a sculpture garden with a cascading fountain, 375-seat auditorium, lecture hall, relocated members' suite, and a public cafeteria. In 1985, the west wing, financed by combined grants of $12 million from Paul Mellon and Sydney and Frances Lewis, and matched by $10 million appropriated by the commonwealth, opened. The 1976 north wing was later demolished to make room for a 100,000 square foot expansion designed by London-based architect Rick Mather, which is expected to open in 2009.
In 1953, the Artmobile program, financed by private donors, businesses and foundations, provided statewide opportunities for education in the arts through traveling programs and exhibits. At the height of the program, there were four Artmobiles in service, including one specifically geared towards college students. The Artmobile program was discontinued in 1994 after 41 years of service.
Established in 1955, the Virginia Museum Theatre was the resident theatre group of the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts. Offering high-quality productions and notable guest performers and directors, the Virginia Museum Theatre brought avant-garde productions as well as popular theatre productions to Richmond. The Virginia Museum Theatre began as a community theatre company and in the 1970s became a 'professional, Equity-affiliated LORT-C theater'. In 1986, the Virginia Museum Theatre became TheatreVirginia, an organization that was independent of the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts. TheatreVirginia continued to present productions at the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts until 2002 when TheatreVirginia ceased operating due to budget constraints.
The Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, through its Office of Statewide Partnerships, has partnered with over 350 nonprofit institutions throughout Virginia to deliver programs, exhibitions to the citizens of Virginia. Now housed in the Pauley Center, the Office of Statewide Partnerships offers crated exhibitions, audiovisual programs, lectures, and workshops in addition to programs specifically geared to students and the educational requirements indicated in Virginia's Standards of Learning program.
The Virginia Museum of Fine Arts is active in many aspects of art and arts education. In addition to active acquisition and exhibitions programs, the Museum offers many instructional programs including lectures, special programs as well as fellowship, apprenticeship and resident programs. An extensive art reference library is available to the general public.
Publications of the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts include a bulletin/calendar and regular exhibition catalogues. Previous publications include "Arts in Virginia" from 1960 until 1993.
Scope and Content
Contains the records of the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts from 1933 until 1977 (bulk 1934-1976). The records are arranged alphabetically by folder title and include annual reports, correspondence, memos, minutes, reports and other materials related to the planning of events, programs and exhibitions at the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts. Of particular interest are the materials regarding the planning of exhibitions, the development of the Artmobile program and the Virginia Museum Theatre, and general planning regarding the future direction and growth of the Museum.
The collection documents the terms of the first three Directors of the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts: Thomas C. Colt, Jr. (1933-1948); Leslie Cheek, Jr. (1948-1968) and James M. Brown (1968-1976). Also documented are the terms of the Associate Directors of the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts during World War II: Violet MacDougall Pollard and Beatrice von Keller and long-time associate director Muriel B. Christison.
Of note in the collection is: the correspondence with members of the Board of Trustees; records of the construction of the original building in 1934 and subsequent additions; and correspondence with various artists, donors and art dealers. Notable correspondents include: Henry W. Anderson; Julien Binford; Alexander Calder; John Canaday; Walter Chrysler, Jr.; Elizabeth Nottingham Day; Horace Day; Jessie Ball duPont; Douglas Southall Freeman; Aldred Geiffert, Jr.; Paul L. Grigaut; Carlisle H. Humelsine; Jay W. Johns; Merrill C. Lee; Paul Mellon; Jo Mielziner; John Lee Pratt; Vincent Price; John D. Rockefeller, III; Aline Saarinen; Eero Saarinen; Edward D. Stone; Lewis L. Strauss; Alexander W. Weddell; E. Randolph Williams; Andrew Wyeth; and Richard Q. Yardley.
In addition to the records documenting the operations of the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, there are numerous records documenting other activities of the director and staff. Leslie Cheek, Jr. was involved in a number of activities including: member of the Fine Arts Advisory Committee for the 1958 World's Fair in Brussels; member of the United States Fine Arts Commission of UNESCO; member of the Fine Arts Committee of the U.S. Air Force Academy; Professional Advisor to the Virginia War Memorial; and United States Coordinator for the international touring exhibition Design in Scandinavia. Violet MacDougall Pollard served as Chair of the Virginia Inter-Agency Committee on Recreation. Muriel B. Christison was active with the Virginia Arts Alliance. Records of these activities are found in this collection, including notes, correspondence, drawings and photographs.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Contents List
- A: General, 1933-1941 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- A: General, 1954-1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- A: General, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- A: General, 1966-1972 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 1)
- A: General, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Accession: Van Clief Estate, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Accessions: First Offers, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Accessions: First Offers, 1935-1936 (OVERSIZE) (Box 79, Folder 1)
- Accessions: First Offers, 1935-1936 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 2)
- Accessions: Mrs. von Keller's File, 1941-1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Accessions: Mrs. von Keller's File, 1941-1945 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 3)
- Accessions Committee: General, 1935-1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Accessions Committee: General, 1935-1950 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 4)
- Accessions Committee: General, 1935-1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Accessions Committee: General, 1935-1956 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 5)
- Accessions Committee: General, 1937-1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Accessions Committee: General, 1937-1945 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 6)
- Accessions Committee: General, 1945-1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Accessions Committee: General, 1950-1953 [1] (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Accessions Committee: General, 1950-1953 [1] (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 7)
- Accessions Committee: General, 1950-1953 [2] (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Accessions Committee: General, 1950-1953 [2] (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 8)
- Accessions Committee: General, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Accessions Committee: General, 1953-1956 [1] (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Accessions Committee: General, 1953-1956 [1], folder 1 of 2 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 9)
- Accessions Committee: General, 1953-1956 [1], folder 2 of 2 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 10)
- Accessions Committee: General, 1953-1956 [2] (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Accessions Committee: General, 1953-1956 [2] (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 11)
- Accessions Committee: General, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Accessions Committee: General, 1956 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 12)
- Accessions Committee: Minutes (incomplete), 1935-1943 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Accessions Committee: Minutes (incomplete), 1935-1943 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 13)
- Accessions Committee: Minutes, 1945-1950 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Accessions Committee: Minutes, 1945-1950 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 14)
- Accessions Committee: 1957 February 26 (Box 90, Folder 1)
- Accessions Committee: 1957 February 26 (RESTRICTED) (Box 91, Folder 1)
- Accessions Committee: 1957 March 18 (Box 90, Folder 2)
- Accessions Committee: 1957 March 18 (RESTRICTED) (Box 91, Folder 2)
- Accessions Committee: 1957 October 14 (Box 90, Folder 3)
- Accessions Committee: 1957 October 14 (RESTRICTED) (Box 91, Folder 3)
- Accessions Committee: 1957 December 7 (Box 90, Folder 4)
- Accessions Committee: 1957 December 7 (RESTRICTED) (Box 91, Folder 4)
- Accessions Committee: 1973 January 9 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Accessions Committee: 1973 January 9, 1972-1973 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 15)
- Accomac - St. James Church (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Accreditation of VMFA by American Association of Museums, 1972-1973, folder 1 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Accreditation of VMFA by American Association of Museums, 1972-1973, folder 2 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Acquisition Reports, 1940-1943 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Acquisition Reports, 1940-1943 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 16)
- Acquisitions: Possible, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Acquisitions: Possible, 1969-1973 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 17)
- Acquisitions: Purchases, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Acquisitions: Purchases, 1973 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 18)
- Activities: Pictures, 1955-1958 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Adams, Mrs. Charles (Anne Fowlkes), 1947 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Adult Program for 1953-1954, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Advisory Committee for the Study of a Museum of Science, etc., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Advisory Council of the Virginia Economy, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Agnew, Thomas and Sons. Ltd., 1953-1960 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Ah, Wilderness Invitations, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Airkem, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Akar Lecture, 1970 September 28, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Akimov, Vladimir, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Albemarle Art Association, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Albemarle Art Association, 1957-1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Albers, Josef, 1949-1954 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Albers, Josef, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Aldheizer, George S., II - Trustee, 1967-1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Aldrich Exhibition, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Alexander Shilling Fund, 1940-1946 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Alexandria Association, 1955-1961 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- American Association of Museums, 1940-1951 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- American Association of Museums, 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- American Association of Museums, 1955-1968 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- American Association of Museums, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- American Association of Museums, 1970-1976 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- American Association of Museums, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- American Association of Museums, 1973-1975, folder 1 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- American Association of Museums, 1973-1975, folder 2 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- American Association of Museums, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- American Association of Museums: Annual Meeting Arrangements - Correspondence, 1959-1962 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- American Association of Museums: Convention 1961 Detroit, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- American Association of Museums: Convention 1962 June 6-8, 1959-1962 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- American Association of Museums: Council Meeting 1974 March 25, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- American Association of Museums: Section Chairman's Reports, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- American Classics of the 18th Century, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
- American Craftsmen's Educational Council, 1949-1958 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- American Federation of Arts, 1945-1954, folder 1 of 3 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- American Federation of Arts, 1945-1954, folder 2 of 3 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- American Federation of Arts, 1945-1954, folder 3 of 3 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- American Federation of Arts, 1945-1954 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 19)
- American Federation of Arts, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- American Federation of Arts, 1955-1961 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- American Federation of Arts, 1959-1965 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- American Federation of Arts, 1960-1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- American Federation of Arts, 1965-1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- American Federation of Arts: 1953 Convention Corning October 29-31, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- American Federation of Arts: 1959 Convention, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- American Federation of Arts: 1959 Convention, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- American Federation of Arts: Minutes of Executive Meetings and Memos, 1959-1965 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- American Institute of Architects, 1947-1958 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- American Institute of Architects Exhibition 1956, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- American Institute of Decorators, 1949-1958 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- American Institute of Decorators (A.I.D.) Exhibition, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- American Institute of Interior Design: Dinner, 1970 May 18, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- American Marine Painting, 1973-1977, folder 1 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- American Marine Painting, 1973-1977, folder 2 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- American Marine Painting, 1973-1977 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 20)
- American Painting, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- American Painting 1950: Special Traveling Exhibition, 1950-1951, folder 1 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- American Painting 1950: Special Traveling Exhibition, 1950-1951, folder 2 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- American Painting 1950: Special Traveling Exhibition, 1950-1951 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 21)
- American Society of Appraisers, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- American Society of Appraisers: Gallery Dinner, 1972 March 29, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Amherst: Executive Committee, Fine Arts Association, 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Anderson, Henry W., 1935-1944 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Anderson, Henry W., 1935-1944 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 22)
- Anderson, Henry W., 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Anderson, Henry W., 1947-1948 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 23)
- Anderson, Henry W., 1948-1954, folder 1 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Anderson, Henry W., 1948-1954, folder 2 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Anderson, Henry W., 1948-1954 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 24)
- Anderson, Henry W., 1949-1954 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Anderson, Henry W., 1949-1954 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 25)
- Anderson, Henry W., Chrysler Dinner, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Annual Meeting: Board of Trustees, 1949-1950 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Annual Meeting: Board of Trustees, 1949-1950 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 26)
- Annual Report, 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Annual Report, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Annual Report 1942-1943: Worksheets, 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Annual Report 1942-1943: Worksheets, 1942-1943 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 27)
- Annual Report, 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Annual Report, 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Annual Report, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Annual Report, 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Annual Report, 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Annual Report, 1948-1949: Worksheets, 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Annual Report, 1948-1949: Worksheets, 1948-1949 (OVERSIZE) (Box 79, Folder 2)
- Annual Report, 1949-1950: Worksheets, etc., 1949-1950 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Annual Report, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Annual Report, 1953 (OVERSIZE) (Box 79, Folder 3)
- Annual Report, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Annual Report, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Annual Report, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Annual Report: Gallery Division, 1949/50-1954/55 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Annual Reports: Gallery Division, 1949/50-1954/55 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 28)
- Annual Reports: First Annual (1935-1936) - Sixth Annual (1940-1941) (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Annual Reports - Seventh Annual (1941-1942) - Ninth Annual (1943-1944) (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Apprentice Training: Inquiries, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Appropriations Committee Hearing, 1964 February 3, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Archaeological Institute of America, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Archer, Edmund, 1935-1945 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Archer, Edmund, 1935-1945 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 29)
- Architecture in Virginia, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Arnson Introduction, 1965 October 18, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Arrival Records, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Arrival Records, 1948 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 30)
- Art Classes, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Art Commission, 1950-1956 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Art Commission, State, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Art Dealers Association of America, Inc., 1970 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Art Film Festival, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Art in Fashion (Thalhimers), 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Art in Travel, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Art Institute of Chicago, 1948-1959 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Art Institute of Chicago, 1969-1973 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Art Jurors - Future, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Art Lovers Society, 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Art Nouveau: Acquisitions, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Art Nouveau: Acquisitions, 1971-1973 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 31)
- Artificial Flowers, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Artist Evenings, 1945-1946 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Artists Evenings, 1953/1954 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Artists' Advisory Committee, 1940-1944 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Artists' Advisory Committee, 1945-1949 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Artists' Advisory Committee, 1948-1950 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Artists' Advisory Committee, 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Artists' Advisory Committee: Ballots, 1945/46 Season (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Artists' Advisory Committee: Ballots, 1946/47 Season (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Artists' Advisory Committee: Ballots, 1947/48 Season (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Artists' Advisory Committee: Ballots, 1948/49 Season (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Artists' Advisory Committee: Ballots, 1950/51 Season (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Artmobile: 1960 Project, 1955-1960 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Artmobile: Alarm System, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Artmobile: Collegiate - College Art Department Heads' Replies, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Artmobile: Fire Extinguisher System, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Artmobile: Fruehauf, 1952-1960 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Artmobile: General, 1949-1953, folder 1 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Artmobile: General, 1949-1953, folder 2 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Artmobile: General, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Artmobile: General, 1953-1957 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Artmobile: General, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Artmobile: General, 1957-1961 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Artmobile: General Motors, 1957-1960, folder 1 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Artmobile: General Motors, 1957-1960, folder 2 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Artmobile: Gertenslager, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Artmobile: Inauguration, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Artmobile: Information Requests, 1953-1961 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Artmobile: Kress Collection, 1956-1958 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Artmobile: Magic City, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Artmobile: Opening - Roanoke, 1958 [1] (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Artmobile: Opening - Roanoke, 1958 [2] (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Artmobile: Operations, 1953-1956 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Artmobile: Operations, 1953-1956 (OVERSIZE) (Box 79, Folder 4)
- Artmobile: Operations, 1953-1956 (RESTRICTED) (Box 75, Folder 32)
- Artmobile: People to People Program, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Artmobile: Pre-Columbian Exhibition, 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Artmobile: Reprints, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Artmobile: Sculpture of Black Africa, 1970-1972, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Artmobile: Virginia Federation of Women's Clubs, 1952-1956 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Artmobile I, 1953-1962 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Artmobile II, 1955-1963 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Artmobile II, 1955-1963 (OVERSIZE) (Box 79, Folder 5)
- Artmobile II: Drawings, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Artmobile II: Drawings, 1961 (OVERSIZE) (Box 79, Folder 6)
- Artmobile II: Opening 1962 September 22, Middleburg, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Artmobile II: Opening 1962 September 22, Middleburg Dinner List, 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Artmobile II: Round 1, 1962 September and October, Photos and Fact Sheet, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Artmobile III: Christening, 1966 September 12, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Artmobile III: Miller and Rhodes - Pratt, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Artmobile IV, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Artmobile IV, 1964-1965 (OVERSIZE) (Box 79, Folder 7)
- Artmobile IV: Carnegie Proposal, 1964-1966 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Artmobile IV: Opening 1966 September 24 Ashland, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Artmobile IV: Program - Carnegie, 1966 April, 1963-1966 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Artmobiles, 1961-1972, folder 1 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Artmobiles, 1961-1972, folder 2 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Artmobiles, 1961-1972 (OVERSIZE) (Box 79, Folder 8)
- Artmobiles, 1974-1977 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Artmobiles: Fruehauf and H and J, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Arts and Crafts Museum Project, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Arts and Humanities Commission (Va.), 1967-1972 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Arts and Humanities Institute Museum Visit, 1971 July 28, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Arts and the National Government, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 26)